#### Vinod Kumar A V - MSc, MBA - IT

7022594868

vinodkumar2478av@gmail.com

#### Professional summary

My experience includes working for clients in the areas of teaching, research, content development and SEO, and marketing support. I am an individual with a passion for learning things related to Science and Technology, Research, Society, Medicine, Crafts such as sketching, painting, guitar, music, current affairs, travel, and many more.

#### Skills

Personality - Balanced, Creative, Knowledge-seeking, Organized, Detail oriented IT - MS Excel, MS Word, MS PowerPoint, WordPress, LinkedIn, Facebook, Twitter, Google+

#### Education

MBA Information Technology | Sikkim Manipal University, Mumbai - 2009

MSc Earth Science & Resource Management | Kuvempu University, Bhadravathi - 2004

BSc Botany, Zoology, Chemistry | Sir M V Govt. Science College, Bhadravathi - 2000

**PUC |** Sir M V Science College, Bhadravathi - 1995

#### Work Experience

#### Content Writer | Access Research Labs | Jul 2022 - Dec 2023

Developing content for websites, articles, blogs, newsletters, social media, video scripts, and technical manuals.

## Freelance and Other Endeavors | Apr 2020 - Apr 2022

Copy Editor - Maintxt, Mysore | Apr 2020 - Dec 2021

NCERT Books and test papers, Healthcare, Science & Technology, K&L, Cornerstones Radiology, Work and Labor Relations, Handbook of Refugee Health, IATI, JCIS, Marketing Research, General Studies, Governance of India, IAS Preparation, etc.

- Editing journals and books for clients across domains such as Science and Technology,
  Economy, History, Sociology Medicine, etc.
- Checking language, consistency, accuracy and clarity
- Ensuring editing guidelines and style sheet guidelines are followed throughout
- Editing as per client requirements such as APA, CUP, Wiley, etc.

## Senior Content Writer | Kido Enterprises - Bengaluru | Feb 2019 - Mar 2020

Projects: Kido Learning app project, Preschool textbook development - Practical Life, Language, Cognitive, Sensorial, Mathematics, Geography, History, Art, etc.

- Developing content for client websites, social media and marketing collaterals
- Developing different levels of preschool curriculum content for children
- Storyboarding and scriptwriting for the learning videos of preschool children
- Creating business emails

### Associate Content Writer | Zenith Software Ltd - Bengaluru | Jan 2018 - Oct 2018

Projects: Awesome Whitsundays, Graylines, Ecozip Adventures, Down Under Down, Autopia Tours, Wildlife Tours Australia, Active Tropics Explorer, Hush HipHop Tours, Real Journeys, Adventure Tours Australia, Arizona Segway and Pedal Tours, Bindlestiff Tours, Bunyip Tours, Chilli's Backpackers, Colourful Trips, Daytur Emirates, Deep Sea Divers Den, Red Buses, Vacation & Cuisine, etc.

- Developing tour content for client websites, updating from back-end, proofreading
- Providing voice support to client technical team (customer project)

#### Marketing | Sahyadri Narayana Multispecialty Hospital | Nov 2016 - Jul 2017

Projects: Hello Doctor Program on ETV Kannada (now News 18), Free Medical consultation camps, Breast cancer screening campaign, World No Tobacco Day, etc.

- Coordinating branding and marketing activities ads, print, audio and visual media, and promotional materials
- Providing back-end support to the marketing team
- Assisting consultants and patients in hospital processes
- Generating reports, preparing medical newsletters, press releases, etc.

### Content Writer | Datascribe Technologies - Bengaluru | Jun 2015 - Aug 2016

Projects: DataLife EHS (Electronic Healthcare Solutions) website and app, Datascribe Digital Marketing website and blogs, Datascribe Medical Transcription website, Datascribe LPO website, Datascribe Tourism website content development. Client projects - StoneTop Granites

- Writing articles, blogs, newsletters, white papers, and press releases for company and clients
- Content for campaigns, websites and online portals like Ezine, Quora, videoscripts and brochures for digital and direct marketing
- Developing and editing content on software development, finance, lifestyle-interiors

### Content Writer | Enthusionz, Bengaluru | Apr 2014 - May 2015

Projects: Pinkathon - breast cancer awareness marathon, Alpha League Race, Tamara Coorg, Snow City, Banashree Developers

- Social media promotion campaigns and posts for the company and clients
- Developing content for a client's e-commerce website

Copy Editor | SR Nova Pvt Ltd. - Bengaluru | Nov 2012 - Mar 2014

Editing and proofreading Chemistry, Medical Case Studies and Reports, Biochemistry, Physics, Mathematics journals conforming to APA, CUP styles

Completing tasks within strict deadlines with optimum accuracy

Search Editor | Yahoo - Bengaluru | Nov 2011 – Jul 2012

Projects Android and iTunes apps

- Optimizing search engine using algorithms
- Trending quality images and videos, articles as per internal standards
- Client Twitter handles and Facebook profiles

Junior Content Writer | Banyan Tree Infomedia LPP - Bengaluru - Jun 2011 - Nov 2011

 Developing content related to the company's Question and Answer website, short articles on Finance, Education, Banking, Lifestyle, Real estate, Interiors, etc.

Trainee Copy editor | MacMillan Publishing Services - Bengaluru | Oct 2010 - Jun 2011

Project: Elsevier

- Editing Biochemistry, Physics, and Chemistry journals
- Experience with various style guides
- Maintaining accuracy and consistency
- Eye for detail, spelling, grammar and punctuation
- Experience in AMA and APA style editing

**Guest Lecturer** | Govt. First Grade College, Kavooru | Govt. Women's First Grade College Mangaluru | Aug 2009 – May 2010

Financial Accountancy, Human Resources, Commercial Law, Business Studies, Business Communication for BBM and BCom

CAD Production Executive | Rolta India Ltd - Mumbai, Maharashtra | Jun 2006 - Oct 2008

- Worked on Electrical and Gas digital conversion projects.
- Worked on the Geo-information System platform to map and convert hardcopy data to digitized information.
- Using softwares to produce geo-referenced maps.

**Research Project:** "Morphodynamics of the Beaches between Redi-Vengurla, Maharashtra" a DST-sponsored Hydrogeomorphological Research Project - JRF

# Junior Research Fellow | GSS College-Belgaum | Feb 2005 – Jan 2006

Prof. Pramod Hanamgond

Collecting ocean sand samples, storage, sieving for gradation of grains, chemical processing and analysis, data management, generating Kurtosis and Skewness graphs

### Internship

"Hydrogeomorphological Study for framing Problem and Prospects of Arkalgud Taluk, Hassan District by Remote Sensing and GIS Techniques"

### **Guides**

Ramesh, K. S., Scientist, RRSSC-ISRO, Bangalore

Dr. G Chandrakantha, Chairman, Department of Applied Geology, Kuvempu University

• Using ArcGIS to map the hydrology and geomorphology of the Arkalgud - region.